<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Callum Rollo - home</title><link href="https://callumrollo.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/home.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://callumrollo.github.io/</id><updated>2025-08-12T13:10:00+01:00</updated><subtitle>Recovering oceanographer</subtitle><entry><title>Recipes</title><link href="https://callumrollo.github.io/recipes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-08-12T13:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T13:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Callum Rollo</name></author><id>tag:callumrollo.github.io,2025-08-12:/recipes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Food that I endorse&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;All of these recipes have been used, adapted  and endorsed by me, an actual human being. They are vegan but don't let that put you off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Aubergine and tomato curry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite spicy. Especially the day after. I love the fennel taste and the chunks of raw garlic and ginger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3cm Cube ginger, chopped pretty coarse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 Cloves garlic, chopped pretty coarse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;800g Aubergines (three medium/2 large)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tsp Fennel seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp Cumin seed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbs Ground coriander seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;½ tsp Turmeric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;400g Chopped tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[optional] 200 g cashew nuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roast aubergine in chunks with veg oil and salt until browned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fry cumin and fennel seeds with oil a for a minute &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add other spices and tomatoes, cook to a paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add aubergine and cashews (if using), cook for 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; Mum. Possibly from a Madhur Jaffrey book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lentil Dahl&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An all time favourite mil flavourful curry.I have prepared this more than any other dish, often tripling the quantity for a dozen people or more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large yellow onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 cloves garlic, finely diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thumb sized piece of ginger, finely diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbs curry paste (e.g. pataks, not sauce!) or 2 tsp curry powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;½ block creamed coconut or 1 tin coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup of red lentils (200 g)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[optional] 100 g spinach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[optional] handful of fresh coriander leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a saucepan fry the onion, garlic and ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add curry powder/paste and fry for a minute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add red lentils and fry until lentils are coated in oil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one tin of coconut milk and 2 cups of water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook until lentils are soft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When cooked, stir in fresh coriander leaves and/or spinach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin:&lt;/strong&gt; Mum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my 17th birthday a dear friend gifted me an A6 blank notebook with a couple of hand drawn illustrations of Gorillaz on the covers. This was intended for use as a journal, but I was several years away from discovering &lt;em&gt;introspection&lt;/em&gt;, so I started writing recipes in it. This book has been everywhere with me and I still consult it on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these recipes were transcribed to a google drive in 2018 by my partner at the time. This has been very useful, but I would like to remove google from my life and self manage my digital presence myself wherever possible. So, I aim to add recipes from the original book and google drive to this website where they can be easily shared with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea for this page came from Elise when she visited Gothenburg in summer 2025. Thanks pal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;An aside on recipes from the web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered why online recipes became so &lt;em&gt;fucking unusable&lt;/em&gt; circa 2015? Basically it's because of SEO (search engine optimisation). The more cruft, long paragraphs and big photos you cram into a web page, the higher google will rank it. This higher google ranks it, the more people will find it. The more clicks you get, the more ad revenue you make. A minimal little text page like this will not be surfaced by google (and I don't monetise via ads lol), but will hopefully help you cook a tasty meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Cooking/comments/w21wjy/comment/ignjhxm/"&gt;nice reddit comment&lt;/a&gt; with some recipe sites that don't suck .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently started using &lt;a href="https://www.paprikaapp.com/"&gt;paprika&lt;/a&gt; to extract recipes from webpages. This has done more to reduce my blood pressure than any amount of statins or low sodium cuisine. I found the app via &lt;a href="https://www.mollywhite.net/"&gt;Molly White&lt;/a&gt; who I respect greatly and has an awesome blog.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="home"></category><category term="home"></category><category term="recipe"></category><category term="list"></category></entry></feed>